or be my subject to the talk and the point of time.
So you've got to meet the third of the papers that we've got.
It's been both out.
That's it.
As we've done this meeting, it's going to be done to
what it's beginning to do.
We've got a discussion.
It doesn't really use to say,
but it seems to be a community.
It's a community.
You see, reading Muhammad from which stands
unsteam, unguided, in start an accessible,
emotive, We're delivering our starts tomorrow.
At 4,
air of the center of the show.
You already like to jump into the What are the sights you have to give you?
If you want to tryと you can double reach me.
Yes.
Your own position will be follow a book,
or a book through someone that was farther that I've gone from...
for the community to continue to work with.
We're really going to support our government,
so we can get your duty to turn into my office.
I know that the conversation allowed by law.
Other than the compensation of our law.
I've heard your daughter come.
I heard her swear her her her.
That I'm faithfully discharged.
I will pay the money this time.
According to the best of my ability.
The duty to do my office.
During such time as I am in my work.
At the limit of my ability.
At thematicity Council.
Tests.
A certain person.
Bye.
Six points.
Accountability.
Passed points.
Motion De Group.
Dec.
On.
On this time, the set of counter.
That.
Out.
So, the points, from rank.
On this.
Motion De Group.
Second.
Dec.
Concert.
On.
Passed.
By.
Concentration.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Thank you, one of the boardmen, I'm really looking to see council law.
I mean, the standard action, the vice president of the building.
I'm sure this is, it's a great week before you again.
The purpose of tonight's presentation, you come and use the mic.
Yeah.
Yeah, but I think this is better.
The purpose of my hopefully great presentation tonight is to go over once again
with the results of the electric race that we prepared for the city of Miami.
We had had the privilege of being a city's great consultants for the last 20 years
and this is about the fourth or fifth electric race that we've done for you.
I've already gone over a lot of this information in the presentation that we did through the last month
but I did include several slides to sort of keep reminding you of what our proposal does
and to further provide these support and needs necessary for the rate plan
that we've recommended for you tonight.
Obviously it's never easy to talk about raising rates, whether they're electric, water, wastewater, or any utility.
This doesn't mean people like to do, nobody wants to pay more for anything at any time for any reason.
But there's a couple of very important factors that the city needs to take into consideration.
First, you try to run your utility like a business.
You want the revenue to be raised to cover all the costs of providing that service.
Electric services is a product.
Electricity is a product, just like a McDonald's, a hamburger or anything else.
And so they cost the city of Miami a certain amount of money to produce that product.
And if you're selling it to your customers, at least the one you're paying to produce it,
then that's not good business for anybody.
Second rule of business is that cost to up.
Can you think of anything that doesn't cost to work today and if I am 10 years younger?
Utility rates are not immune to that, basically all of that can obviously be.
All of this to want to keep our rates as low as possible.
It is a good goal of any city of any utility to try to minimize or keep their rates as low as possible.
Okay, but the problem is when you utility.
has to balance the desire to keep rates low with the need to invest in your system to ensure
that you continue to provide a high level of service. So that means that the lowest rates
are not always the best rates. I work for many many utilities. I work over 200 utilities across
the United States and the six foreign nations. And I work for some utilities to have incredibly low rates,
but they have low rates because they don't invest in their system. And so the quality of the service
and quality is deteriorating significantly, that's not necessarily a good way to run the utility.
And so all these factors are going into the need to propose a new long-term electric rate
time to the city. But I would say that it really comes down to four factors.
There are four factors more than anything else that are driving the need for a hundred-way time.
First is inflation. But cost everything goes up three to four percent a year.
Just do an inflation. So it's reasonable to expect over time your cost is going to get higher for
that reason alone. Second of all, you buy the purchase power from GRDA. In fact, the majority of the
costs of providing electric service here in the city of Miami is due to the cost that you pay GRDA for the
purchase power. Well guess what, everything they're raised on you. Everybody in 11 percent rate increase this year.
And there are implementing four percent rate increases in 2026 and 2027. So there are different ways
that we're going to see whether you raise your rates or not. So if you have no choice to pass these costs to
your customers and that means higher rates. Third reason is that the city plan is on the issue when you
28 million dollars a day to fund a electric system capital infrastructure improvements. Now the good news is that
that's going to be to a better and more reliable while you're service. But that's $18 million
has to be funded somehow. One of the benefits of running a utility boat is that the money that you ask
good ratepayers to contribute goes directly back into the city in terms of $20 million dollars in the
new investment. So that's the third reason. And the fourth reason is that you have got the grant for your
A&I program. The A&P unfortunately the grant doesn't cover all the costs. And as it's typical
the federal government grants, they will pay the lying share of it, but they expect utility utility to pay
portion of it as well. And so your portion of it is totally in the costs. So if you think of these four
backwards here, those are the reasons why we're going to regret many new rate planning. Just a couple of
months ago, real brief background charts here. His chart right here is a historical projection
of your electric customers. As you can see, your electric customers are actually new. I'm sorry about that.
As you can see, your total question is actually declining a little bit over the last
by years from 6800 to 6600, but we're projecting that you're going to see some very, very
modest growth over the next five to 10 years.
This chart right here, this rather cold for chart right here, is a historical blood depiction
of your G&B8 pile of costs.
Look, G&B8 generates the electricity that they sell to you.
A lot of their costs are due to what I'm sorry, a bit of a ton of time.
But a lot of their costs are due to the cost of the world oil and gas that they use to
generate their electricity.
So in a sense, they're performing a positive student world oil and gas prices as well.
As you can see over the last five years, they're caused kind of ballooned up and came down.
And that mirror, a lot of the increases in decrease in world gas prices.
The good news is that the last 12 pounds cost will come way down.
And it's my professional opinion as a economist that gas prices are going to stay down in the next couple
of years.
You have new administration that is much more agreeable to the idea of natural gas in all
of production.
And I think that's one key oil prices in gas prices as well.
And I think that's going to benefit you as they sit it because the lower costs are going to be
reflected in gear in the cost to you.
But unfortunately, their costs are going to get higher in the short term.
Okay, we'll also talk about the capital improvements.
What?
What is this $28 million going to go with the fund?
Well, this is just a listing of the projects that are slated to be funded with the $28 million
in debt that this rate plan will fund.
In addition to the AI program, you're looking at upgrades to your substations 3, you're looking
at reconventures and poll change apps, which is very common, all electric utilities have to do
that.
You're looking at upgrades in the feeder 23, build out of substations 4, and you're just seeing
that solar carbon development.
So all of these factors are invested in this, but cost a lot of money, build on electricity,
cost a lot of money and maintain it.
And like any other asset, it wears out a whole time.
And it has to be maintaining, upgrade it, and replace, and that's what this rate plan is going
to fund for you.
As you can see, this is $28 million in debt that we are, that we're projecting, and the city is
going to be issuing over the next 10 years.
Now, obviously, you're not going to be, but an issue at all costs, you're going to be issuing
the savings, which is good financial management, don't borrow a line for you, don't borrow
a project that's going to do it.
So, but...
You can also see a lot of debt that's going to have to be issued very quickly in the next two years.
Then after that, you're going to have to be issued more debt over a period of time.
But once again, that's why we're able to phase in the race that are going to be necessary to fund all of these projects.
So this chart right here, I want to follow the numbers here.
But this chart right here is recurring and forecast-costed service.
A couple of very important things to keep in mind as you review this chart.
It's broken down into the elements of costs that are incurred by the city in providing like-exervice.
Operating costs, as you can see, go up our project, go up gradually over the next four years.
Obviously, no sense costs, whatever it goes up, three to four percent here.
Purchase power, as you can see, your purchase power costs are going to go up.
And I think the world is much as they otherwise do, because oil and gas prices are going to stay down.
But GREA is still implementing greater increases that are reflected in this protection here.
You've got some capital outlets that are being funded.
This is your debt service. You've got current debt, and this is the forecast new debt that is going to be issued.
And then you've got transfers of about $3 million to support the general fund from the electric fund.
That's once again a very common element of electric service.
Bottom line is that your total cost of service is $24 million right now, and it's expected to go up to about $27 million over the next three years.
So, we're going to, the numbers we're presented tonight are not only different from what we saw last month.
They're basically the same, but the biggest change we've made is that we're recommending to need three year implementation now, whereas I'm not going to regret it in the two year implementation.
So, that will need to be the phase and end of a slightly longer period of time.
We're recommending that we do in your, in your non-GRDA cost, a 1% increase effective in June or July of 2025.
That would be followed by an adjustment January 26, which would be a $4 increase in your base charge.
And a 5% increase in your buy-hunter charge.
And then in January, 2027, we recommend another 5% increase.
We also recommend that you continue assessing your PTA charge, which is the past group of the PCH charge, and is a assessed U of 5GRDA.
Good news is, we think that number is still going to be very, very long.
Oh, that is something the effect we think is going to be basically zero over the next few years.
But, a couple of things also have been considered.
While we are recommending an increase in July of 2025, your PCA X-Tcharge is going to phase out or be eliminated in July.